Ibragim Zubailov @karlson.zim@gmail.com | to LinkedIn | Telegram | Gitlab

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Senior Software Engineer with experience in: Node.js, Go, Database, Team & Tech Leadership.

Business-oriented, flexible, communicative, with an emphasis on results.

With experience in load under 500k rps(input), and number of users (up to 1 million)

Worked with **Enterprise** and **Startup** companies, in teams from 3 to 20 people.

Project type experience: AdTech(OpenRTB), Gambling, Blockchain, GameDev, Storage

SKILLS

Programming: Go, TypeScript, Node.js, NestJS, Web3(Blockchain) Storage: Clickhouse, Postgres, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, Aerospike Transport: Kafka, RabbitMQ, NATS, GRPC, GraphQL, Websockets

Others: GlusterFS, ElasticSearch, Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible, Nginx, Prometheus, Grafana

Languages: Russian (native), English (intermediate)

WORK EXPERIENCE (6 YEARS)

MTS Group

Senior Software Engineer

Moscow, Russia · Remote Jun 2022 — Jun 2023 (1v.)

Project: Distributed data storage system, B2B internal

- Identified a balance issue between storage systems and developed a service to optimize load handling.
- \bullet Eliminated a bottleneck in data retrieval from storage, increasing performance 10x.
- Facilitated team operations by creating tools for workflow simplification, which enhanced overall team productivity.

Stack: Go, Node.js, Clickhouse, MongoDB, Kafka, RabbitMQ, GlusterFS

NDA

Part-time

Senior Software Engineer

May 2022 — February 2023 (10m.)

Project: CS:GO Gambling, GameDev: Jackpot, Mines, Crash, Roulette, Coinflip, Case Opening, Upgrade

- Full development of the backend for the gaming platform, including: business logic, architecture, DevOps.
- Microservice architecture, framework for rapid game creation, deployment pipeline, monitoring, logging, scaling.

Stack: Node.js, Postgres, Socket.IO, Nginx, Prometheus, Grafana, Ansible, Docker

Lofty

 $Moscow, Russia \cdot Hybrid$

Lead Software Engineer (8 BACKEND GO DEVELOPERS)

Project: Automated Traffic Arbitrage

May $2020 - \text{May } 2022 \ (2y.)$

- Analyzed data to pinpoint key growth areas for advertising arbitrage (**OpenRTB**).
- Streamlined team processes: incorporated **KPIs**, a roadmap, an idea board, task decomposition.
- Devised a traffic quality forecasting system to optimize costs and filtering for SSP.
- Conceived and developed a system for assessment and filtration (Antifraud), ensuring quality for DSP.
- Boosted the annual profit from 0 to 1 million USD in two years, in high-load product with under 500k rps.

Stack: Go, Clickhouse, Postgres, Aerospike, Kafka, GRPC

Lead Software Engineer (4 BACKEND NODE.JS DEVELOPERS)

Oct 2019 — May 2020 (8m.)

Project: SSP (Supply Side Platform), Push, Inpage, Native, Popunder (AdTech)

- Overhauled an application to achieve stability, **3x** performance, and A/B testing capability, which enabled performance enhancement **from 15k to 150k RPS** over two years.
- Implemented Agile, optimized hiring and staff adaptation processes.
- Contributed to architectural design and DevOps, enhancing data storage efficiency.

Stack: Node.js, Clickhouse, Postgres, Redis, Kafka

Senior Software Engineer

Jul $2019 - \text{Oct } 2019 \ (4m.)$

Project: SSP — Push notifications Stack: Node.js, MySQL, RabbitMQ

- Developed a high-load (70k rps) service for sending push notifications with extensive customization options.
- Created a microservice for authorization.

Belsona Investment Group Middle Software Engineer

Moscow, Russia · On-site Jun 2017 — Jul 2019 (2y.)

Stack: Node.js, TypeScript, MySQL, Web3(Ethereum.), Websockets

- Engineered a bot for arbitrage between **blockchain smart contracts** and exchanges (**Binance/Bitfinex**).
- Created a risk assessment and predictive market trend model based on blockchain data.
- Implemented automated scripts to reduce routine tasks, particularly for ICO projects.
- Developed a service for calculating risks of ICO products.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree, Computer and Information System Security Dagestan State University Sep $2013 - \text{May } 2017 \ (4y.)$